<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Meerman]]></title><description><![CDATA[Meerman.xyz website and blog]]></description><link>https://meerman.xyz/</link><generator>RSS for Node</generator><lastBuildDate>Thu, 07 Aug 2025 19:50:22 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://meerman.xyz/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><managingEditor><![CDATA[Dries Meerman]]></managingEditor><webMaster><![CDATA[Dries Meerman]]></webMaster><ttl>180</ttl><item><title><![CDATA[The journey of starting a blog]]></title><description><![CDATA[In this article, the author reflects on their journey of starting a blog after completing their Master's degree, driven by a desire to enhance their writing skills, conduct research, and share knowledge. They discuss the essential requirements for their blog, including the need for control over its hosting, a preferred Markdown format for writing, and the implementation of RSS feeds for content distribution. Choosing a custom tech stack, they extended their existing website using Rollup, Svelte, and Markdown plugins while improving the appearance with Tailwind CSS. They automated RSS feed generation with the help of ChatGPT, although future enhancements, such as automating image publishing and addressing Markdown footnotes, are considered. The article concludes with a reminder to prioritize project completion over perfection and to utilize available tools for efficiency.]]></description><link>https://meerman.xyz/#/blog/dr-001</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://meerman.xyz/#/blog/dr-001</guid><pubDate>Sun, 28 May 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Finishing projects]]></title><description><![CDATA[This article explores the common issue of unfinished side projects and suggests techniques to overcome it. The author discusses the challenge of side projects losing momentum over time due to the absence of external pressures like deadlines. They emphasize the importance of completing projects, as it hones valuable skills, allows for user feedback, and frees up mental space for creativity. The 'Cult of Done Manifesto' is referenced to underscore the significance of finishing. To prevent projects from languishing, the author recommends preparation, cheating by using existing components, setting clear goals, and collaborating with others. These strategies help maintain focus, enhance productivity, and increase the likelihood of project completion. Ultimately, the article acknowledges that there is no foolproof solution but suggests that these techniques have proven effective for the author in finishing more projects.]]></description><link>https://meerman.xyz/#/blog/dr-002</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://meerman.xyz/#/blog/dr-002</guid><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Hybrid automation for one-off tasks]]></title><description><![CDATA[The blog post titled 'Hybrid Automation' explores a practical approach to combining automation and manual tasks to achieve optimal efficiency. The author introduces the concept of hybrid automation, where automation is applied to tasks that are easily automated, and manual tasks are retained if they are not too tedious and don't benefit significantly from automation. The post delves into the Pareto Principle, commonly known as the 80/20 rule, where 80% of outcomes come from 20% of causes, emphasizing the efficient use of resources. The author provides a real-life example involving the automated downloading of images from a website and explains how they leveraged the ChatGPT tool to simplify the process. They describe the creation of scripts for obtaining image links, copying the data to the clipboard, and a bash script for downloading the images. The post concludes by highlighting the benefits of breaking tasks into manageable components that can be easily automated or manually executed to bridge gaps effectively.]]></description><link>https://meerman.xyz/#/blog/dr-003</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://meerman.xyz/#/blog/dr-003</guid><pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2023 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Swift 5.9 - TL;DR]]></title><description><![CDATA[Swift 5.9, released with Xcode 15.2, introduces significant language improvements, including bi-directional C++ compatibility, macros, and the use of 'if' and 'switch' as expressions for more readable code. Debugging sees a speed boost, particularly in 'p' and 'po' commands, and there are notable enhancements to the Swift Package Manager and the Swift-syntax project. The author is particularly excited about the potential for cleaner code with 'if' expressions and the anticipated improvements in code analysis tools. This update also brings advancements for Swift on Windows platforms.]]></description><link>https://meerman.xyz/#/blog/dr-004</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://meerman.xyz/#/blog/dr-004</guid><pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Artificially enhanced IDE's and sidequests]]></title><description><![CDATA[The article discusses the Dries' experience with using AI-enhanced IDEs, specifically Cursor, to address issues on their website, including markdown flavour inconsistencies and large bundle sizes. Initially hesitant to fix these problems due to their complexity and existing functionality, the author explores how AI can assist in making the process faster and less tedious. They delve into the complexities of markdown variations and their desire to implement footnotes, eventually using AI to optimize the site's structure and reduce bundle sizes. While the AI helped streamline tasks, it also introduced some minor bugs, such as incorrect file capitalization, highlighting both the potential and limitations of AI-driven development. Overall, the author found AI tools useful for problem-solving and workflow improvements, despite occasional challenges.]]></description><link>https://meerman.xyz/#/blog/dr-005</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://meerman.xyz/#/blog/dr-005</guid><pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Exploring the Model Context Protocol]]></title><description><![CDATA[Inspired by recent advancements in agentic AI like VS Code's agent mode and Google's Agent2Agent protocol, the author explores the Model Context Protocol (MCP), an open standard allowing Large Language Models (LLMs) to request external context and utilize tools for more accurate, less hallucinatory results. Motivated to apply this to their ServiceNow expertise, the author developed a custom MCP server (available on GitHub) to retrieve table schemas, detailing the building process using official guides and the MCP Inspector tool for local testing. The article concludes by demonstrating the successful integration of this server into the Cursor editor, where an LLM agent uses the custom tool to fetch live ServiceNow data and generate code based on it, showcasing MCP's potential to enhance AI coding assistants with reliable, real-world context and actions.]]></description><link>https://meerman.xyz/#/blog/dr-006</link><guid isPermaLink="true">https://meerman.xyz/#/blog/dr-006</guid><pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 00:00:00 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>